准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
爸妈大万岁
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
牛油果公寓区
疗养社区
啊  牛油果公寓区
Ah, Avocondo Acres
裤头村的顶级疗养社区
Bikini Bottom's premier retirement community
在这能找到哈罗德和玛格丽特
This is where we find Harold and Margaret
这对父母诞下了全海洋
the parents of the ocean's
最不寻常的多细胞生物
most exceptional multicellular organism
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
哈罗德  你闻到了吗
Harold, did you smell that?
好像有什么东西
It smells like something
烂掉了
rotting
已经开始了
It's begun
最好马上逃
We better run
都跟人说了要用柠檬汁擦房子
I tell people to rub their homes with lemon juice
再用塑料包起来
and wrap it in plastic
可他们有听我话吗
But do they listen?
哈罗德  我们该怎么办
Oh, Harold, what will we do?
就只能再种一个新家了
Well, we'll just have to grow a new home
在这期间
And in the meantime
可以跟儿子一块住
We can stay with our son
快找掩护  小蜗
Take cover, Gary
看好了
Watch this
我跳上跳下
I jump up and down
汽水瓶盖就会爆开
The soda bottles pop their corks
然后危险万分带我整间房到处冲
and send me careening dangerously around the room
我很有可能活不下去
I may not survive
喂
Hello?
妈妈好
Hi, Mom
爸爸好
Hi, Dad
你们家
Your house?
不会吧
Oh, no
跟我一块住
Stay with me?
那是当然可以的了
Why, of course you can
你猜怎么着  小蜗
Guess what, Gary
爸妈要第一次来我们家住了
Mom and Dad are coming over
to stay at our place for the very first time
我刚想到点事
I just thought of something
我爸妈有好些日子没见我了
My parents haven't seen me in a while
他们可能会期望看到儿子变得更加
They'll be expecting their son to be a little more
就是  成年
well, adult--
大人  成熟
grown-up, mature--
你再看看我
and look at me
看看这地方
And look at this place
又脏又乱
It's a filthy mess
躲猫猫
Peek-a-boo
干净
Clean
我看到你了
I see you
好干净
So clean
什么
What?
必须别再这么碰面了
We gotta stop meeting like this
你上完了吗
You almost done?
会不会很有意思呢  亲爱的
Won't this be fun, dear?
我好期待
I'm looking forward to
能跟儿子那样的新潮都市年轻人一块
hanging out with a hip, young urbanite like our boy
没错  亲爱的
Oh, yes, dear
我们真的特别需要
We can really use
往内心注入年轻精神  活力
an injection of youthful spirit, vitality
甚至是莽撞
and dare I say, recklessness
爸爸妈妈你们好
Hello, Mater, Pater
真是天大的荣幸
This is truly a pleasure
不进来吗
Won't you entrer?
进去之后
所以说
So
我们今天要干什么
what are we gonna do today?
等不及要进城里去了
I can't wait to hit the town
我冒昧写了一份活动日程
I have taken the liberty of
writing up an agenda of activities
里面内容对于我们大人都十分刺激
that I know all of us adults will find most stimulating
首先要在这附近散散步
We'll begin with a leisurely walk
about the neighborhood
共同评价别人家的草坪
so we can critique other people's lawns
在那之后
After that--
讨论税款  政治
conversations about taxes, politics
政治             税款
所有东西烂透了
还有现在的事物有多么大不如前
and how things aren't nearly as good as they used to be
然后早早吃一顿晚饭
then an early-bird dinner
下午四点以睡觉结束这一天
and we'll top it off with bedtime at 4:00 pm
可是儿子  这不
But son, this isn't--
可以的  儿子
Whatever you say, son
我们是你客人
We're your guests
下午四点钟
4:00 in the afternoon
一点热牛奶
Some warm milk
还有舒缓的啧啧牢骚声
and the soothing sounds of disapproval
可以帮你们快快入眠
to whisk you off to your slumbers
你们都被禁足了
You are so grounded
你能不能不要再吵了
Will you puh-lease stop that confounded racket?
有大人还想在里面睡觉
Some grown-ups are trying to sleep in here
抱歉先生
Sorry, sir
什么
What?
等一下
Wait a minute
晚安  我亲爱的蜗牛
Good night, my dear gastropod
玛格丽特  亲爱的
Margaret, dear
恐怕儿子已经变成了
I'm afraid our son has become
就是  老古板
well, a fuddy duddy
用词可能不是很恰当
Pardon my language
我觉得这里
Well, I was gonna say
很失望  压抑
"bummer, a downer
还特别乏味
and a total drag"
咱要不要一起溜出去找点乐子
What do you say we sneak out and have some fun?
老早就想这样了
Way ahead of you
你们两个去哪了
Where have you two been?
都已经晚上八点了
It is 8:00 at night
我担心得要命
I was worried sick
我们只是在找点乐子
We were just having a little fun
你们两个表现得跟小孩一样
You're both acting like children
你表现得跟个方正老古板一样
And you're acting like a square
我本来就方正
I am square
而且我已经下定决心要表现成熟
and I've already committed to acting mature
不管你们喜不喜欢
whether you like it or not
行吧  成熟先生
Okay, Mr. Mature
你现在倒也得来找点乐子了
it's time for you to have some fun
不管你喜不喜欢
whether you like it or not
裤头村狂欢夜开始了  宝贝
It's Bikini Bottom after dark, baby
绝对疯得不得了
It's gonna be wild
上啊  儿子
Go on, son
跟她一起玩
Join her
必须给我去  儿子
That is an order, son
好
Okay
宝刀未老
I still got it
快啊  扫兴鬼
Come on, killjoy
别老这么扫兴
Don't be such a party pooper
快扔
Do it
实在太幼稚了
This is so childish
这是怎么
What is going--
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
蒙面摔跤
Masked luchador wrestling
年少无知
How juvenile
也还行吧
Well, I guess this is all right
应该也疯不到哪去
It shouldn't be too wild
光坐在这看着就好
just sitting here, watching
我们不是来这光看的
We're not here to watch
我们是来摔的
We're here to wrestle
组合摔跤时间到
It's tag team time
组合摔跤
时间
大恶魔对战爸妈组合
Los Diablos vs Madre y Padre
妈  爸
Mommy, Daddy
不要
no
妈  爸
Mom, Dad
我来了
I'm coming
妈
Mom?
爸
Dad?
好小子  海绵宝宝
'Atta boy, SpongeBob
我们支持你  小子
We're rooting for you, kiddo
下一轮比赛
For our next bout
死神对战花生袋先生
it's El Muerte vs Señor Peanuts Bag
等等  什么
Wait, what?
妈  爸
Mommy, Daddy
别再来了
No más
好不好玩啊
Now, wasn't that fun?
那个戴着花生袋的哪去了
Where'd that peanut bag guy go?
我饿了
I'm hungry
热狗要不要
How 'bout a hot dog?
24小时轮滑场
我都不知道
I never even knew
裤头村有家24小时营业的轮滑场
there was a 24-hour roller rink in Bikini Bottom
估计在轮滑场里慢慢滑也疯不到哪去
Well, I guess skating slowly
around and around a roller rink isn't so wild
场里
Rink?
我们要溜遍全城
We're skating through town
不好意思
Excuse me
你们两个能不能表现成熟点
Will you two please act your age?
别滑了
Please stop
能不能慢点
Will you slow down?
太疯狂了
This is crazy
手套乐园
算我求你们了
Please, I beg you
我只想给你们留下好印象
I just wanted to impress you two
在你们面前当个成熟大人
by showing you what a mature adult I've become
可你们偏不  净想着疯
But no, you wanted wild
那行
Okay, fine
你们想疯
You want wild?
就给你们瞧瞧
I'll show you
疯
Wild
儿子睡着了  累坏了
The boy's asleep, all tuckered out
我们新种的牛油果公寓应该快熟了
Well, our new avocondo should be ripe right now
他只能先跟我们住一段时间了
He'll have to stay with us
等菠萝屋重新长出来再回去
until he can regrow his pineapple
想知道
I wonder
他何时才会真正成长成熟
when he'll really grow up and be mature
但愿不会太早
Hopefully not too soon
对吗  亲爱的
Am I right dear?
花生袋先生
Señor Peanuts Bag
我要伤害赔偿
I want satisfaction
花生也行
Or peanuts
我比较想吃花生
I'd rather peanuts
黄 道
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
影片开始
海中安全
安全驾驶教育影片
各位学员大家好
Hello, student drivers
我是泡芙老师
I'm Mrs. Penelope Puff
按照法院的命令
and as per the court order
我会在这部教育影片中担任教练
I will be your driving instructor in this education film
只要记牢138条简简单单的交规
By remembering these 138 simple rules of the road
你们大家自然就能心领神会
every one of you will know all that you need
考到驾照的必备知识
to get your very own boating license
墙
连我都会吗
Even me?
五点预查
第一课
First lesson
这位是好司机先生
Here we have Mr. Good Driver
在把船发动之前
Before starting the vehicle
为确保安全  他会检查船的五个区域
he always inspects five areas of his boat for safety
他检查了轮胎浮力
He checks his tire buoyancy
确保螺旋桨润滑充分
Ensures his propeller is properly oiled
确认船上汽笛正常运作
Confirms his boat horn is functioning
复查信号旗
Reviews his signals
最重要的是
And most importantly
他系好了安全带
he fastens his seat belt
另外的这位是差司机
And here we have a bad driver
我称之为  海绵宝宝
or what I refer to as a "SpongeBob"
检查胎压
Check tire pressure
润滑螺旋桨  完成
Oil propeller, check
检查汽笛  完成
Check horn, check
快让开
Out of the way
检查信号旗  完完成成
Check signals, checkerino
安全带
Seat belt
带上了
Belted
我现在能领驾照了吗
Can I get my license now?
不能
上路
现在进入第二课
Now to our second lesson
开船上路时
As he begins his journey
好司机先生
Mr. Good Driver
都会仔细观察左右来船
makes sure to watch carefully for oncoming boats
只有等前方没有来船了
Only when the road is clear
他才会加速驶入道路
does he accelerate into traffic
美味热狗
我能领驾照了吗
Can I get my license now?
不能
注意行人
第三课
Lesson three
路上会有多种不同的行人
There are several types of pedestrians
于是好司机先生都会留意观察
So Mr. Good Driver always keeps careful watch
前面出现了灵巧的小老太太
Here we have the cunning little, old lady
还有坐着童车的咿咿呀呀小宝宝
And the babbling baby in a buggy
普普通通的水果摊
The common fruit vendor
当然  前面还有几个工人
And naturally, we see some workmen
搬着一大块玻璃
carrying a large pane of glass
好老套
How cliché
好司机先生也许自认为能放松警惕了
Mr. Good Driver may think he can let his guard down
但还有一位行人正等着攻其不备
but there's still one pedestrian waiting to strike
稀有物种  恼人海绵
The rare Poriferous Aggravatus
恼人海绵
俗称  海绵宝宝
commonly known as a SpongeBob
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
我能领驾照了吗
Can I get my license now?
胶卷丢失
导航
第29课
Lesson 29
好司机先生一定要按交通标识行船
Mr. Good Driver must obey various road signs
下面是一些例子
Here are just a few
注意减速带
Speed bumps
前方玩耍儿童慢行
Slow children at play
有时候  连好司机先生
Sometimes, even Mr. Good Driver
都有可能被方向弄迷糊了
may be overwhelmed with directions
驾驶时不得看地图
Never read a road map while driving
只有海绵宝宝会这么做
That's something only a SpongeBob would do
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
正确的乘员礼节
第53课
Lesson 53
安全驾驶同样意味着
Good driving also means
乖乖当好乘员
being a good passenger--
不害司机分心
never distract your driver
你猜怎么着  章鱼哥
Guess what, Squidward
我今天要领到驾照了
I'm gonna get my license today
泡芙老师说影片拍完
Mrs. Puff said, at the end of the film
我就有驾照了
I'm gonna get it
你会领到的
You're gonna get it all right
不在后座对司机指手画脚同样重要
It's also important not to be a backseat driver
我可以坐在后座开船吗
I can drive from the back seat?
住手
Stop it
你害我快疯了
You're driving me crazy
最后  作为乘员
Finally, as a passenger
绝对不能随意玩弄中控
you must never play with the boat's control console
来放点音乐听听
Let's get some tunes going here
不然来开空调吧
How 'bout some AC?
太冷了
Too cold
我来帮你一把吧
Let me help you with that
不要
Oh, no
不
No
路怒症
第54课
Lesson 54
连好司机先生都很有可能忍不住
Even Mr. Good Driver may be tempted
对同行的司机大发雷霆
to take out his anger on a fellow motorist
在这样的情况下
In times like these
要记住一个简单的词
remember one simple word--
怒
放松
再
绕
到别处
这个我会
I know this one
我来帮你放松  朋友
Let me help you relax, friend
深深吸气
Just breathe in
再呼出来
And out
行了
That's it
要不要喝杯放松心情的海草茶
Now, how about a relaxing cup of kelp tea?
是不是清爽宜人啊
Refreshing, right?
来扫沙子吧
Now, let's rake some sand
好  放松
There, relaxed
现在要绕到别处了
Maybe it's time to go elsewhere
破烂投影仪
This darn projector--
一到最精彩的部分就坏了
just when we were getting to the good part
你放心  泡芙老师
Don't worry, Mrs. Puff
让好学生来帮你继续
Let a good noodle handle that for you
不用  海绵宝宝
No, SpongeBob
没关系
that's okay
我准备好演特写镜头了
I'm ready for my close-up
给我出来
Get out of there
是  老师
Yes, ma'am
看来影片放不完了
Well, I guess we can't finish the film
可  可要是影片放不完
B--b--but if we can't finish the film
课就上不完了
we can't finish class
要是上不完课
And if we can't finish class
我就领不到驾照了
then I can't get my license
有了
I know
我亲自来演完影片
I'll finish the film myself
现在是万众期待的时刻
And now, the moment you've all been waiting for
驾照
海绵宝宝
海绵宝宝的驾照
SpongeBob's boating license
海绵宝宝是个极具模范意义的司机
SpongeBob was such an exemplary driver
得了吧
Puh-lease
市政厅为了纪念他  举办了特别仪式
That a special ceremony was held
市政厅
in his honor at city hall
此时此刻  梦想成真
It was a dream come true
泡芙老师坚信他配得上脚下的道路
Mrs. Puff had deemed him worthy of the road
他最终领到了耀眼的  真正的
He finally had a dazzling, genuine
实物大小的驾照
full-sized boating license
满怀着高超的驾驶技术
Now, imbued with the power of good driving
海绵宝宝向混乱世界中的人民们
SpongeBob brought peace to the people
带来了和平
of this troubled world
他把蟹黄堡送给了饥民
He delivered Krabby Patties to the hungry
制止了违法小罪
He de-escalated petty crime
还阻止了冰盖融化
And he even kept the ice cap from melting
没错  大家此时此刻最爱海绵宝宝
Yes, everyone loved SpongeBob more than ever
因为他成功领到了驾照
now that he had his boating license
大家深深爱着他
They all loved him so much
差不多得了
That is quite enough
下周继续上内容正常的课
We'll resume the correct lesson next week
下课
Class is dismissed
把今天学到的知识记牢了
Just remember what you learned today
不准再胡闹了
and no more of this nonsense
是  泡芙老师
Yes, Mrs. Puff